

Full Stack Software Engineer

Full Stack Software Engineer with over 9 years of experience in software development. As a full stack .Net developer, I specialize in developing web and mobile applications using .Net technologies and Javascript framework for front-end environment. I also focused on developing scalable and welldocumented code, enjoying working collaboratively or developing projects independently.



♠ https://www.elmersanpedro.com
✓ dev.esanpedro@gmail.com
↓ +63 9952812511
♠ https://github.com/devesanpedro

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

07/2021 - Present

Vibe Technologies Inc., Quezon City, Philippines

- Design and implement web applications based on client requirements.
- Responsible for all front-end development such as web application using latest frameworks (Angular 15 and React).
- Develop and maintain Rest Web API using Repository and CQRS pattern with latest .net framework (.Net 7 and .Net Core)
- Develop and maintain databases using MS SQL and PostgreSQL technologies and design database tables and complex functions, scripts, stored procedures and triggers to support system and backend processes.
- Perform unit testing in development side using built in method in .Net framework.
- Identify bottlenecks and bugs, and devise solutions to these problems.
- Protects internal operations and database data by keeping information confidential.

Senior Program Analyst

09/2019 - 08/2021

Vertere Global Solutions Inc., Makati, Philippines

- Design and implement web applications based on client requirements.
- Responsible for all front-end development such as web application using latest frameworks (Angular 15 and React).
- Develop and maintain Rest Web API using Repository and CQRS pattern with latest .net framework (.Net Core)
- Develop and maintain database using PostgreSQL. Design database tables and complex functions, scripts, stored procedures and triggers to support system and backend processes.
- Perform unit testing in development side using built in method in .Net
- Identify bottlenecks and bugs, and devise solutions to these problems.
- Protects internal operations and database data by keeping information confidential.

Senior Software Engineer

03/2018 - 09/2019

SPI Global Inc., Parañaque City, Philippines

- Design and develop internal system and application.
- Responsible for all front-end development such as web application using latest Angular framework.
- Develop and maintain Rest Web API using Repository pattern with latest .net framework (.Net Core)
- Develop and maintain database using MySQL. Design database tables and complex functions, scripts, stored procedures and triggers to support system and backend processes.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2010-2014 - BS Computer Science

Cavite State University, Main

LANGUAGES

- Filipino (Native)
- **English**

TRAININGS

- SAFe 5.0 for Teams
- Microsoft Azure Deployment
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

HARD SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

- Front-end: Angular, React, ASP.Net MVC, Bootstrap, Material Design, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript
- Back-end: .Net 7, .Net Core
- Database: MS SQL, MySQL, **PostgreSQL**

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

- Platforms: Windows, WinRT, Android
- Back-end: .Net Core, .Net Framework
- Database: MS SQL, MySQL

OTHERS

Azure, AWS, Google Cloud, JIRA, Azure DevOps, CICD, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Repository, CQRS

WANT TO KNOW MORE?

Visit my online CV by scanning the QR code:



Windows Developer

Virtualidad Inc., Quezon City, Philippines

- Translate application storyboards and use cases into functional applications.
- Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable C# code.
- Translate design specification into functional windows app and games.
- Implement game functionality as per communicated design.
- Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications.
- Contributes to team by giving ideas, analysis and related results as needed.

Programmer Analyst

04/2014 - 04/2015

Asian Hospital and Medical Center, Muntinlupa, Philippines

- Arranges project requirements in programming sequence by analyzing requirements; preparing a work flow chart and diagram using agile methodology for software and system development.
- Confirms program operation by conducting prototype testing; modifying sequences and codes.
- Design database tables and complex functions, scripts, stored procedures and triggers to support system and application development.
- Protects internal operations and database data by keeping information confidential.
- Provides technical advice and support to users. This includes creating ad-hoc reports, data analysis and integration services.

PROJECT

HRIS PRIVATE

A web and mobile based human resouce information system. It is a subscription based application with a full integrated functions for HR processes and centralizing HR related data. *Technologies: Angular, .Net 7, PostgreSQL, MS SQL*

RMC HRIS (Rizal Medical Center)

A web-based information system used by Rizal Medical Center (RMC) which is one of the government agencies of the Philippines. It is a fully integrated system for HR processes and centralizing HR related data.

Technologies: .Net MVC, .Net Core, MS SQL

PRC HRIS (Professional Regulation Commission)

A web-based information system used by Professional Regulation Commission (PRC) which is one of the government agencies of the Philippines. It is a fully integrated system for HR processes and centralizing HR related data.

Technologies: .Net MVC, .Net Core, MS SQL

NAP HRIS (National Archieves of the Philippines)

A web-based information system used by Professional Regulation Commission (PRC) which is one of the government agencies of the Philippines. It is a fully integrated system for HR processes and centralizing HR related data.

Technologies: .Net MVC, .Net Core, MS SQL

UL Field Services

An e-Commerce web-based application used to sell and cater client order and request services.

Technologies: React, .Net Core, PostgreSQL

Editorial Web Application

An internal web-based application used by researchers to gathered specific entity data and stored in the application database.

It is used for data mining and sell-out the data in third-party client.

Technologies: Angular, .Net Core, MS SQL

RevUp

A web-based application used by operators to automate manual processes such as document scraping, file conversion, and email extraction with respective report generation.

Technologies: Angular, .Net Core, MS SQL

SmartHR

A web-based human resource information system for Virtualidad Inc. employees to access their personal records, timekeeping, benefits, and payroll details.

Technologies: .Net Framework, MS SQL

V-Smart

A web-based human resource information system for Virtualidad Inc. employees to access their personal records, timekeeping, benefits, and payroll details.

Technologies: Windows App, WinRT, C#

Tranvia Runner

A multi-platforms mobile game application for the Megaworld Chinatown Museum. It aims to give ideas and information to the new generation of student about the local trading in the 18th Century Philippines.

Technologies: Unity 3D, C#